const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"A 25-year-old male presents to the emergency room with sudden urinary retention and lower limb weakness. The neurosurgeon is called, urgent surgery is recommended after relevant imaging studies. To establish a diagnosis of cauda equina syndrome, besides the aforementioned symptoms, what other clinical feature must be present?","answers":[{"option":"Increased muscle tone","bool":false},{"option":"Brisk reflexes in lower limbs","bool":false},{"option":"Saddle anesthesia","bool":true},{"option":"Bilateral foot drop","bool":false},{"option":"Increased bulk below knee joints","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following statements is true regarding post-dural puncture headache?","answers":[{"option":"It is relieved within 12 hours by an epidural blood patch","bool":false},{"option":"It is noted immediately","bool":false},{"option":"It is aggravated by the supine position","bool":false},{"option":"It is most frequent with large-bore needles","bool":true},{"option":"It is not lessened by the use of a Whitacre needle as compared to a Quincke needle","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following is not an indication for a X-ray?","answers":[{"option":"Patellar fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Skull fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Detection of calcification in brain","bool":true},{"option":"Palpable head vertex injury","bool":false},{"option":"Headache","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"A 45-year-old man presents to the clinic with complaints of a chronic, dull headache, that feels like a tight band around his head. His headache is associated with neck stiffness but there is no association with nausea, vomiting, or photophobia. He has had this complaint for one year now. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Classic migraine","bool":false},{"option":"Cluster headache","bool":false},{"option":"Trigeminal neuralgia","bool":false},{"option":"Tension headache","bool":true},{"option":"Giant cell arteritis","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following is the most appropriate first step in the immediate management of a patient presenting to the emergency room with status epilepticus?","answers":[{"option":"Draw blood to send for complete blood count","bool":false},{"option":"Ensure patent airway access","bool":true},{"option":"Administer intravenous diazepam 10 mg","bool":false},{"option":"Administer etomidate for intubation","bool":false},{"option":"Give the patient general anesthesia","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"According to the McDonald criteria for the diagnosis of multiple sclerosis, if a patient has 2 episodes separated in time and space, with clinical evidence of at least 2 lesions on MRI, what further investigations are required for the diagnosis of MS?","answers":[{"option":"Wait for another episode as further imaging needed","bool":false},{"option":"Wait 1 year to assess disease progression","bool":false},{"option":"No further requirement as clinical evidence alone suffices","bool":true},{"option":"Wait for seeing a rise in intracranial pressure to perform lumbar puncture","bool":false},{"option":"Wait for another lesion with additional attacks","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"A couple has brought their 6-year-old child to the outpatient department with the complaint that he has been remaining inattentive in class and seems to go blank and stare in space. There is no other significant past medical history. What is the going to be the most likely finding on electroencephalography (EEG)?","answers":[{"option":"Slow wave pattern","bool":false},{"option":"3 Hz spike-and-wave","bool":true},{"option":"Hypsarrhythmia","bool":false},{"option":"Centrotemporal spikes","bool":false},{"option":"High voltage discharges","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following conditions is a neurodegenerative disease?","answers":[{"option":"Epilepsy","bool":false},{"option":"Subarachnoid hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Multiple sclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Poliomyelitis","bool":false},{"option":"Alzheimer disease","bool":true}]},{"id":8,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following bacteria is a known cause of meningitis and can be diagnosed by Quellung reaction?","answers":[{"option":"Neisseria gonorrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":true},{"option":"Salmonella enterica","bool":false},{"option":"Haemophilus influenzae","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following is a common infectious agent found in children after contracting an upper respiratory tract infection?","answers":[{"option":"Haemophilus influenzae","bool":true},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Neisseria meningitidis","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"A 45-year-old male presented to the outpatient department with a painful vesicular rash on his face. He is diagnosed as a case of shingles. What is the most common causative organism for this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Varicella zoster virus (VZV)","bool":true},{"option":"Poxvirus","bool":false},{"option":"Cytomegalovirus","bool":false},{"option":"Herpes simplex virus (HSV)","bool":false},{"option":"Poliovirus","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following is the most likely to be the earliest finding in Parkinson disease?","answers":[{"option":"Bradykinesia","bool":false},{"option":"Ataxic gait","bool":false},{"option":"Rigidity","bool":false},{"option":"Tremors","bool":true},{"option":"Clonus","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following is true regarding acute viral encephalitis?","answers":[{"option":"Protein > 700 mg/dL","bool":false},{"option":"There is polymorphic leukocytosis","bool":false},{"option":"Herpes RNA is detected by polymerase chain reaction (PCR)","bool":false},{"option":"Acyclovir 10 mg/kg 3 times daily for 2-3 weeks is given","bool":true},{"option":"Glucose is raised","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which organism can cause meningitis in a child consuming unpasteurized milk?","answers":[{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Listeria monocytogenes","bool":true},{"option":"Neisseria meningitidis","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium botulinum","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following best describes pleocytosis in the cerebrospinal fluid?","answers":[{"option":"Presence of erythrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in lymphocyte count","bool":true},{"option":"Decrease in glucose levels","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in protein levels","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in glucose levels","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Damage to which area of the brain can cause alexia and agraphia?","answers":[{"option":"Cingulate gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"Broca","bool":false},{"option":"Prefrontal cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Frontal cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Left angular gyrus","bool":true}]},{"id":16,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"What type of speech is observed in patients with mania?","answers":[{"option":"Sing-song","bool":false},{"option":"Disorganized (word salad)","bool":false},{"option":"Incoherent","bool":false},{"option":"Poverty of speech","bool":false},{"option":"Flight of ideas","bool":true}]},{"id":17,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following is the most common type of hallucination in schizophrenia?","answers":[{"option":"Auditory","bool":true},{"option":"Visual","bool":false},{"option":"Tactile","bool":false},{"option":"Gustatory","bool":false},{"option":"Hypnagogic","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following is true regarding Guillain-Barr√© syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"It is an infective polyneuropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Relapsing and remitting course","bool":false},{"option":"Miller Fisher syndrome is a common variant","bool":false},{"option":"Tendon reflexes are preserved","bool":false},{"option":"Acute demyelinating inflammatory polyneuropathy","bool":true}]},{"id":19,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Sensorineural deafness is an integral part of which disease?","answers":[{"option":"Neurofibromatosis type 1","bool":false},{"option":"Acoustic schwannoma","bool":true},{"option":"Trigeminal neuralgia","bool":false},{"option":"Medulloblastoma","bool":false},{"option":"Glioblastoma","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"What is the anatomical localization of the structure involved in a 'glove and stocking' pattern type of neurological deficit?","answers":[{"option":"Cerebral cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Nerve root","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"Peripheral nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Brainstem","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which pathway carries pain, temperature, touch, and pressure sensations?","answers":[{"option":"Spinocerebellar pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Spinothalamic pathway","bool":true},{"option":"Sensory pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Spinocerebellar pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal column","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"A lesion at the level of the optic chiasma leads to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Homonymous quadrantanopia","bool":false},{"option":"Complete loss of vision","bool":false},{"option":"Homonymous hemianopsia","bool":false},{"option":"Heteronymous bitemporal hemianopsia","bool":true},{"option":"Unilateral hemianopsia","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"What is the duration of action of lignocaine?","answers":[{"option":"Long","bool":false},{"option":"Very long","bool":false},{"option":"Intermediate","bool":true},{"option":"Very short","bool":false},{"option":"Short","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following statements is most accurate regarding myasthenia gravis?","answers":[{"option":"IgG antibodies against acetylcholine receptors are the main cause","bool":true},{"option":"Weakness improves with exercise","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory involvement is common","bool":false},{"option":"Sensory involvement may occur","bool":false},{"option":"D-penicillamine may relieve transient myasthenia gravis","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which cranial nerve carries sensory information in the corneal reflex?","answers":[{"option":"Cranial nerve IV","bool":false},{"option":"Cranial nerve VII","bool":false},{"option":"Cranial nerve V","bool":true},{"option":"Cranial nerve XI","bool":false},{"option":"Cranial nerve III","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Neuroleptic agents have maximum effect in which of the following symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Apathy","bool":false},{"option":"Interest","bool":false},{"option":"Sleep","bool":false},{"option":"Apetite","bool":false},{"option":"Hallucinations","bool":true}]},{"id":27,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"A pregnant lady was given a local anesthetic after which she developed severe anaphylaxis. Which drug was most likely given to her?","answers":[{"option":"Tetracaine","bool":false},{"option":"Ropivacaine","bool":false},{"option":"Lidocaine","bool":false},{"option":"Bupivacaine","bool":false},{"option":"Procaine","bool":true}]},{"id":28,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"What is the immediate complication of spinal puncture for anesthesia?","answers":[{"option":"Urinary retention","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothermia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypotension","bool":true},{"option":"Blurry vision","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"An unvaccinated, 18-month-old child is brought to the clinic with left lower limb weakness. His parents say that he had fever and diarrhea two days ago, which was managed with oral rehydration salts (ORS). Which of the following investigations is the most appropriate?","answers":[{"option":"CT spine","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray","bool":false},{"option":"MRI","bool":false},{"option":"Stool viral antigen","bool":true},{"option":"Lumbar puncture","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"A 40-year-old male is taking antipsychotics for ten years. He has developed tardive dyskinesia. This effect is due to the lack of which of the following neurotransmitters?","answers":[{"option":"Dopamine","bool":true},{"option":"Serotonin","bool":false},{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"Histamine","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following is a therapeutic indication for a lumbar puncture?","answers":[{"option":"Meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Guillain-Barre syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Idiopathic intracranial hypertension","bool":true},{"option":"Subarachnoid hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Multiple sclerosis","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"A 54-year-old man is brought to the emergency department because of altered loss of consciousness after being severely injured in a road traffic accident. The patient opens his eyes to pain; his pupils are reactive and equal. There is no verbal response, and his limbs extend abnormally when stimulated by pain. Which of the following is the score of this patient on the Glasgow coma scale (GCS)?","answers":[{"option":"4","bool":false},{"option":"1","bool":false},{"option":"5","bool":true},{"option":"8","bool":false},{"option":"3","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following antipsychotic agents has effects at the serotonin receptor?","answers":[{"option":"Promethazine","bool":false},{"option":"Risperidone","bool":true},{"option":"Haloperidol","bool":false},{"option":"Thioridazine","bool":false},{"option":"Chlorpromazine","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following is the most common mechanism of action of antipsychotic drugs?","answers":[{"option":"Alpha-adrenergic activity","bool":false},{"option":"Increase serotonin levels","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease dopamine levels","bool":true},{"option":"Decrease norepinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Beta-adrenergic activity","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"What is the mechanism of action of vigabatrin?","answers":[{"option":"Blocks acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"Increases GABA levels","bool":true},{"option":"Activates potassium channels","bool":false},{"option":"Inactivates sodium channels","bool":false},{"option":"Blocks calcium channels","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"What is the mechanism of action of lacosamide?","answers":[{"option":"Inactivates potassium channels","bool":false},{"option":"Activates potassium channels","bool":false},{"option":"Inactivates sodium channels","bool":true},{"option":"Blocks calcium channels","bool":false},{"option":"Increases GABA","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which class of drugs does amitriptyline belong to?","answers":[{"option":"Selective serotonin re-uptake inhibitors","bool":false},{"option":"Serotonin-norepinephrine re-uptake inhibitors","bool":false},{"option":"Monoamine oxidase inhibitors","bool":false},{"option":"Tricyclic antidepressants","bool":true},{"option":"Heterocyclic antidepressants","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Children should be prescribed valproate with caution due to the risk of which of the following side effects?","answers":[{"option":"Gingival hyperplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Paralytic ileus","bool":false},{"option":"Vomiting","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatotoxicity","bool":true},{"option":"Anorexia","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following is a major risk factor for most forms of dementia?","answers":[{"option":"Advanced age","bool":true},{"option":"Smoking","bool":false},{"option":"Lifestyle","bool":false},{"option":"Genetic cause","bool":false},{"option":"Environmental factor","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"A man presents to the emergency and head CT findings show a crescent-shaped lesion. Which of the following is not a risk factor for this patient's disease?","answers":[{"option":"Anticoagulant","bool":false},{"option":"Shaken babies","bool":false},{"option":"Trauma","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic kidney disease","bool":true},{"option":"Chronic alcoholism","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following foods is given to a stroke patient?","answers":[{"option":"Sugary food","bool":false},{"option":"Pureed food","bool":true},{"option":"Salty food","bool":false},{"option":"Food rich in saturated fat","bool":false},{"option":"Sauteed food","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following is used for treatment of resistant schizophrenia?","answers":[{"option":"Clozapine","bool":true},{"option":"Chlorpromazine","bool":false},{"option":"Benzodiazepines","bool":false},{"option":"Risperidone","bool":false},{"option":"Olanzapine","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"What is the initial choice of investigation for a patient who presents with signs and symptoms of suspected acute stroke?","answers":[{"option":"Lumbar puncture","bool":false},{"option":"Magnectic resonance imaging (MRI)","bool":false},{"option":"Electroencephalography (EEG)","bool":false},{"option":"Contrast MRI","bool":false},{"option":"Non-contrast CT","bool":true}]},{"id":44,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Excessive autonomic activation is a feature of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Depression","bool":false},{"option":"Autism","bool":false},{"option":"Phobia","bool":false},{"option":"Panic","bool":true},{"option":"Psychosis","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"Which of the following agents is a weak anesthetic but a potent analgesic and thus is given with other inhalants?","answers":[{"option":"Etomidate","bool":false},{"option":"Nitrous oxide","bool":true},{"option":"Midazolam","bool":false},{"option":"Halothane","bool":false},{"option":"Thiopental","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2019","question":"An 80-year-old patient with asthma and low blood pressure required anesthesia for an emergency surgical procedure. Which of the following is the anesthetic of choice?","answers":[{"option":"Etomidate","bool":false},{"option":"Ketamine","bool":true},{"option":"Desflurane","bool":false},{"option":"Thiopental","bool":false},{"option":"Propofol","bool":false}]}]
export default arr